So we understand how to create some elements with HTML,
我们已经知道了如何创建 HTML 元素
and we understand that we can write CSS code to style particular elements.
也知道了可以使用 CSS 给元素添加特殊样式
But how do we actually execute our code in the editor?
但是我们如何在编辑器里让它们生效呢？
I mean how do we connect the CSS and the HTML?
也就是说如何把 CSS 和 HTML 连接起来呢？
Well, you have options.
有多种方式
There are three main ways to link CSS to your HTML code,
有 3 种主要的方式可以把 CSS 应用到 HTML 上
and I'll quickly show you an example of
我会给你看一些例子
each and then you'll continue learning about them on your own.
然后你可以自己继续学习它们
The first is called inline,
第一种方式是内联方式（Inline）
the second are style tags,
第二种是使用 style 标签（Style tags）
and the third are external stylesheets.
最后一种是使用外部样式表（External stylesheets）
One way that perhaps you've seen is through linking an external stylesheet.
你可能已经见过外部样式表的使用方式了
To link an external stylesheet,
为了引入一个外部样式表
you create a link with a relationship stylesheet,
你需要创建一个 link 标签 设置 rel 属性为 stylesheet
a type, text CSS.
和一个 text/css 的 type 属性
Here is our href attribute which you may remember.
最后是你可能还记得的 href 属性
Our href attribute goes to styleDemo.css So
这里我们设置了 href 属性为 styleDemo.css
let's go into our folder and we see here we have styleDemo.css.
在这个文件夹里我们也可以看到有一个 styleDemo.css 的文件
So one way that we could do this,
选中一个 ID 是 test 的元素
is we could say here we have an ID test. So there's one way.
并设置颜色为红色 好了 这就是其中一种方式了
We can use an external stylesheet here,
我们使用了一个外部样式表
which we've linked in head of our HTML document,
并在 HTML 里面引入它
and then it reads perfectly to this.
然后就可以完美生效了
A second way is called inline CSS.
第二种方式是使用内联 CSS
Inline CSS lets you actually add the CSS code as an attribute,
内联 CSS 允许你通过属性添加 CSS 代码
in the front tack of a div.
把它放置在 div 的开始标签内
So for example, here we have our div,
举个例子 这里有一个 div
and as we learned in HTML we have an ID attribute,
和一个我们已经学习过的 ID 属性
but we can also have a style attribute.
但是它也可以有一个 style 属性
Here the style attribute lets you write CSS rules directly onto a div.
可以通过 style 属性 直接将 CSS 规则写入 div 元素
So right now this div has style font size 54 px,
所以这里的 div 会有 54 像素的字体大小
but if we change it to style font size 14 px,
如果我们把字体大小设置为 14px 的话
we see a shrink right down.
可以看到它变小了很多
So see that these also work in connection.
而且你可以看到它们同时生效了
I'm calling both this CSS,
在外部 CSS 文件里
which is giving me the color red,
我们设置了颜色为红色
and on an inline style I'm setting the font to be 14 points.
然后在内联样式里 我们把字体大小设置成了 14 像素
But that's not it.
除此之外
There's a third way you can do this which are to put
还有第三种添加样式的方式
style tags directly inside your header.
就是在 header 内部使用 style 标签
So notice in our header here,
在 header 这里可以看到
we've linked an external style sheet.
我们引入了一个外部样式表
But if we don't want to do that,
但是如果我们不想这样做的话
we could put style tags directly in here and then
我们也可以直接在这里放置一个 style 标签
any CSS we write will go directly into our HTML.
然后在里面给我们的 HTML 元素添加想要的样式
So let's do this.
让我们来试一试
Let's say text-decoration uppercase.
我们把 text-decoration 设置为 uppercase
I think this is a property,
应该是这个属性
we'll find out together.
我们一起看看
It's going to be text transform I think actually.
它应该会对我们的字体产生一些变化
Then we see uppercase.
好了 字体变成大写了
So now, we have CSS coming from an external sheet,
所以 我们可以使用外部样式表添加 CSS 样式
we have CSS that's coming from within style tags in the header,
也可以通过在 header 内部使用 style 标签添加
and we have inline CSS directly on the element.
或者直接在元素上使用内联 CSS
Now, to be clear in the real world,
不过 在现实情况中
I think you would rarely use all three of these in one project.
你应该很少会在一个项目中使用所有的方式
For different instances, you might use one or the other.
在不同的情况下 你可能会使用不同的方案
Often the style tags are good when you're just trying to
在你不想把文件拆分成两部分时
throw something together and you don't want to have two files yet.
使用 style 标签是一种很好的方式
But ultimately, when you're working on a professional project,
但是 在做一个专业的项目时
we talk about separating concerns.
我们会考虑到关注点分离
So it's going to be helpful for you to know how to have your CSS in a separate file.
这时 把你的 CSS 放在不同的文件就会是一种很好的选择
But while we're going along in this lesson,
不过在这节课中
you'll often see me use these style tags in the header because
我们通常会直接在 header 内使用 style 标签
they work just fine and they're great for demonstration.
因为用来演示它已经足够了
You can choose your own way to put it in CSS.
你可以自由选择使用 CSS 的方式
It's really up to the imagination.
看你喜欢哪种了